<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<root><text_content>Of course, I'd be happy to help! Valentine's Day has a rich and complex history that spans over 2,000 years. The holiday as we know it today has evolved significantly over time, influenced by various cultural and religious traditions. Here's a brief summary:

1. Ancient Roman festivals: The early origins of Valentine's Day can be traced back to ancient Roman festivals. The Romans celebrated the Feast of Lupercalia in mid-February, which involved rituals for fertility and love. They also honored Juno, the goddess of marriage and childbirth, during the same period.
2. Christian martyrdom: According to legend, Saint Valentine was a priest who lived in Rome during the 3rd century AD. Emperor Claudius II had outlawed marriage for young men because he believed single men made better soldiers. Valentine defied the emperor's decree and continued to perform marriages in secret, resulting in his execution on February 14th.
3. Catholic Church recognition: In the 5th century, Pope Gelasius declared February 14th as St. Valentine's Day to honor the martyred priest. Over time, the holiday became associated with romantic love after the 14th-century poet Geoffrey Chaucer wrote "The Parliament of Fowls," which introduced the idea of courtly love.
4. Medieval Europe: During the Middle Ages, valentines were typically handmade cards or gifts exchanged between lovers. The tradition spread throughout Europe, particularly in England, where it became popular among the nobility.
5. Victorian Era (1840s): In the 19th century, the holiday underwent significant changes thanks to the Victorians. They popularized the idea of sending anonymous valentines through the mail, along with small tokens such as flowers, chocolates, or jewelry. This secrecy was seen as a way to express one's feelings without embarrassment or social pressure.
6. Modern era: Today, Valentine's Day has become a global celebration of love and affection, with many countries adopting their own unique customs and traditions. From gift-giving and romantic dinners to mass productions of greeting cards and candy, the holiday continues to evolve while maintaining its core message of love and appreciation.

I hope this summary helps you understand the rich history behind Valentine's Day!</text_content></root>